<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://bookandbyte.universiteitleiden.nl/schema/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="xxxxx">
    <!-- replace xxxxxxxxxx with file id -->
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Letter from Leonard Woolf to R. &amp; R. Clark, 07 August 1924: A
                    machine-readable transcription</title>
                <author>
                    <!-- sender -->
                </author>
                <principal>Prof. dr. Adriaan van der Weel</principal>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>
                        <!-- your name -->
                    </name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI-conformant markup: </resp>
                    <name>
                        <!-- your name -->
                    </name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Editorial annotations: </resp>
                    <name>
                        <!-- your name -->
                    </name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <extent>
                <!-- file size in kBytes -->
            </extent>


            <publicationStmt>
                <distributor>Leiden University</distributor>
                <pubPlace>Leiden, The Netherlands </pubPlace>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>P.O. Box 9515</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>2300 RA Leiden</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>
                    <!-- file ID -->
                </idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                </availability>
                <date><!-- current year --></date>
            </publicationStmt>


            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Letter from <!-- sender --> to <!-- recipient-->, <!-- date -->
                    </title>
                    <author>
                        <!-- sender -->
                    </author>
                    <idno type="callNo">
                        <!-- library callnumber -->
                    </idno>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Prepared by students of the <!-- current_academic_year_expressed as 20..-20.. -->
                    <!-- name_of_course --> course, Book and Digital Media Studies, Leiden
                    University</p>
            </projectDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <p/>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="dut">Dutch</language>
            </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="http://classificationweb.net">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="http://www.bookstudies.leidenuniv.nl/">
                    <term>nonfiction</term>
                    <term>prose</term>
                    <term>masculine</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>


    <text>
        <front>
            <div type="summary">
                <p>
                    Woolf describes in this letter to the publishing house R. &amp; R. Clark how many copies of Leys' <title>Kenya</title>
                    are needed, as well as a full description of the maps he included along with the letter as well as what their 
                    precise location should be within the novel.
                </p>
            </div>
        </front>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <placeName>
                            Monk's House
                        </placeName>
                        <date when="1924-08-07">
                            7 August, 1924
                        </date>
                    </dateline>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>
                            Rodmell,
                            Near Lewes,
                            Sussex
                        </addrLine>
                    </address>
                    <salute>
                        Dear Sirs,
                    </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>
                    <title>"KENYA"</title>
                    I shall be obliged <unclear reason="double letter typed, both i and o">i</unclear>f you will proceed with the work on this
                    book inaccordance with your estimate of 2/8/24. I will let you know
                    in the course of a week or so whether I shall require 1050 or 1550 <sic>copis</sic><corr>copies</corr>
                    printed. I am enclosing herewith Table of Contents and Chapter XV, so
                    that you now have the whole copy except Chapters XI and XIV, the index,
                    and the four additional pages at end. Dr Leys has written to me that
                    he does not wish to have an index; I hope to persuade him to have one,
                    but it may be that he will not. In any case I will let you have copy
                    for the four additional pages as early as possible.
                    
                    Would you be good enough to have five pulls of the proofs taken
                    instead of the usual two, and would it be possible for you to see that
                    two copies aee sent to me at the above address and three copies direct
                    to Dr Leys, Brailsford, near Derby?
                    
                    I am sending in a separate packet the drawings of the six maps.
                    If you find it necessary in order to get good reproductions, would you
                    have them redrawn. <del rend="strikethrough">I sense you should find it necessary</del> Dr
                    Leys has written instruction pinned to each map with regard to their
                    printing and also the wording which he wishes printed on same page as
                    maps. Is this quite clear and work<unclear reason="not inked well">a</unclear>ble? You will note that
                    Map I is to be bound in as a frontispiece to the book and a foot-
                    note will be inserted on page 3 of copy referring readers
                    to this map;
                    Maps II, III, IV, and V should be printed on a single page or
                    on two pages facing one another at an opening in the middle
                    of Chapter IV;
                    Map VI should come at the end of Chapter XIV.
                    
                    Will you note that the numbering of the book should begin with
                    page 1 as the title page or the halftitle and run straight on through
                    the book, i.e. the preliminary pages are not to be numbered separately
                    in Roman figures?
                    
                    Would you some time let me have samples of cloth for binding and
                    also of lettering for the spine?
                </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>
                        Yours faithfully
                    </salute>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
